Inkyu Shin | Curriculum Vitae

☑ dlsrbgg33@kaist.ac.kr

I am a third-year Ph.D. student at Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology (KAIST) under the co-supervision of Prof. Kuk-Jin Yoon and Prof. In So Kweon. I earned my B.S and M.S degrees in automotive engineering from Hanyang University(HYU) and KAIST in 2019 and 2021. I interned at NEC Laboratories America, Inc, San Jose, CA (with Dr. Yi-Hsuan Tsai), and Google Research (with Dr. Liang-Chieh Chen, and Dr. Jun Xie)

Research Interests

My research interest lies in computer vision, with a focus on developing effective learning method for processing data and building strong recognition models. Specifically, I am interested in the following research topics:

Learning for Data-efficiency

Learning from Simulation Domain Adaptation Unsupervised Learning Self-supervised Learning

Learning for Visual Recognition

Image Segmentation Video Segmentation

but also open to other explorable/challenging domains.

The ultimate purpose of these researches is to apply to a variety of applications (e.g., Autonomous driving, Robot Navigation, AR/VR).

Research Experience

LA, CA (virtual) Google Research May 2022 - April 2023 Student Researcher Intern, Mentors: Liang-Chieh Chen and Jun Xie **NEC Laboratories America, Inc** San Jose, CA (virtual) Research Intern, Mentors: Yi-Hsuan Tsai May 2021 - Aug 2021 Korea University Seoul, Korea Research Intern, Supervisor: Jaegul Choo Sep 2018 - Dec 2018 Hanyang University Seoul, Korea Research Assistant, Supervisor: Myuong-Ho Sunwoo Jul 2018 - Aug 2018

Education

Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology (KAIST)

Future Vehicle Ph.D. degree, Co-Advisors: Kuk-Jin Yoon and In So Kweon

2021–

Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology (KAIST)

Future Vehicle M.S degree, Advisor: In So Kweon

Master's Thesis: Learning to Scale the Labels for Self-training based Domain Adaptation

Hanyang University (HYU)

AUTOMOTIVE ENGINEERING B.S degree

Seoul, Korea
2013–2019

Publications

(C: conference / J: journal / P: preprint / * :equal contributions)

International Conference.....

[P4] Video-kMaX: A Simple Unified Approach for Online and Near-Online Video Panoptic Segmentation

Inkyu Shin, Dahun Kim, Qihang Yu, Jun Xie, Hong-Seok Kim, Bradley Green, In So Kweon, Kuk-Jin Yoon, Liang-Chieh Chen **arXiv**, 2023

o [P3] MATE: Masked Autoencoders are Online 3D Test-Time Learners

Muhammad Jehanzeb Mirza*, **Inkyu Shin***, Wei Lin*, Andreas Schriebl, Kunyang Sun, Jaesung Choe, Horst Possegger, Mateusz Kozinski, In So Kweon, Kuk-Jin Yoon, Horst Bischof **arXiv**, 2023

[C11] TTA-COPE: Test-Time Adaptation for Category-Level Object Pose Estimation
 Taeyeop Lee, Jonathan Tremblay, Valts Blukis, Bowen Wen, Byeong-Uk Lee, Inkyu Shin, Stan Birchfield,
 In So Kweon, Kuk-Jin Yoon
 Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR), 2023

[C10] Bidirectional Domain Mixup for Domain Adaptive Semantic Segmentation
Daehan Kim*, Minseok Seo*, Kwanyong Park, Inkyu Shin, Sanghyun Woo
Association for the Advancement of Artificial Intelligence (AAAI), 2023

- [C9] Learning Classifiers of Prototypes and Reciprocal Points for Universal Domain Adaptation Sungsu Hur, Inkyu Shin, Kwanyong Park, Sanghyun Woo, In So Kweon Winter Conference on Computer Vision (WACV), 2023
- [C8] Moving from 2D to 3D: volumetric medical image classification for rectal cancer staging Joohyung Lee*, Jieun Oh*, Inkyu Shin, You-sung Kim, Dae Kyung Sohn, Tae-sung Kim, In So Kweon Medical Image Computing and Computer Assisted Intervention (MICCAI), 2023
- o [C7] MM-TTA: Multi-Modal Test-Time Adaptation for 3D Semantic Segmentation Inkyu Shin, Yi-Hsuan Tsai, Bingbing Zhuang, Samuel Schulter, Buyu Liu, Sparsh Garg, In So Kweon, Kuk-Jin Yoon

Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR), 2022

- Received Qualcomm Innovation Award 2022.
- o [C6] UDA-COPE: Unsupervised Domain Adaptation for Category-level Object Pose Estimation Taeyeop Lee, Byeong-Uk Lee, Inkyu Shin, Jaesung Choe, Ukcheol Shin, In So Kweon, Kuk-Jin Yoon Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR), 2022
- [P2] Unsupervised Domain Adaptation for Video Semantic Segmentation Kwanyong Park*, Inkyu Shin*, Sanghyun Woo, In So Kweon arXiv, 2021
- [C5] LabOR: Labeling Only if Required for Domain Adaptive Semantic Segmentation Inkyu Shin, Dong-Jin Kim, Jae Won Cho, Sanghyun Woo, Kwanyong Park, In So Kweon International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV), 2021 (Oral)
 - Received Qualcomm Innovation Award 2021.
- [P1] Learning Representations by Contrasting Clusters While Bootstrapping Instances

Junsoo Lee, Hojoon Lee, **Inkyu Shin**, Jaekyoung Bae, In So Kweon, Jaegul Choo arXiv, 2020

o [C4] Discover, Hallucinate, and Adapt:

Open Compound Domain Adaptation for Semantic Segmentation

Kwanyong Park, Sanghyun Woo, **Inkyu Shin**, In So Kweon Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems (**NeurIPS**), 2020

- Received Qualcomm Innovation Award 2021.

o [C3] Two-phase Pseudo Label Densification for Self-training based Domain Adaptation Inkyu Shin, Sanghyun Woo, Fei pan, In So Kweon

European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV), 2020

- Also presented at "Visual Learning with Limited Labels" Workshops in conjunction with (CVPR), 2020

${\color{gray}\bullet} \ \ [\text{C2}] \ \, \textbf{Unsupervised Intra-domain Adaptation for Semantic Segmentation through Self-Supervision}$

Fei pan, Inkyu Shin, Francois Rameau, Seokju Lee, In So Kweon Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR), 2020 (Oral)

- Received Qualcomm Innovation Award 2020.

o [C1] Image-to-Image Translation via Group-wise Deep Whitening-and-Coloring Transformation

Wonwoong Cho, Sungha Choi, David Keetae Park, **Inkyu Shin**, Jaegul Choo Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (**CVPR**), 2019 (**Oral**)

Awards

o 2022: Qualcomm Innovation Award.

o 2021: Qualcomm Innovation Award.

o 2020: Qualcomm Innovation Award.

IT skills

o Languages: Python, MATLAB, C, LATEX

o Libraries: PyTorch, TensorFlow

References

o Prof. In So Kweon

Relationship: M.S & Ph.D Advisor Professor, Electrical Engineering, KAIST

Email: iskweon77@kaist.ac.kr

o Prof. Kuk-Jin Yoon

Relationship: Ph.D Advisor

Professor, Mechanical Engineering, KAIST

Email: kjyoon@kaist.ac.kr

o Dr. Yi-Hsuan Tsai

Relationship: Internship mentor at NEC Lab. (Previous) Research scientist, NEC Lab. (Current) AI/ML Tech Lead Manager, Google

Email: wasidennis@gmail.com

o Dr. Liang-Chieh Chen

Relationship: Internship mentor at Google Research (Previous) Research scientist, Google Research (Current) Research scientist, ByteDance Email: lcchen@cs.ucla.edu